Kevin Edey

Edmonton, AB edeymailbox@gmail.com 780 243 1357

I am a computer programmer and designer with a passion for creating and building software that solves problems. My coding is researched, planned, organised and commented. My specialty is diversity as I am continuously improving upon and learning new languages. I am a mature, reliable person and enjoy collaborating with other programmers and with people from other areas of the business and incorporate open and honest communication in my daily work. Recent research suggests an organization's collective intelligence is set by the communication abilities and social intelligence of the members irrespective of the member's individual intelligence. That is why I place a strong emphasis on communication and I am a naturally friendly person.

Career

Web / Mobile Developer (Contractor)

Kwiksol Corporation August - October 2015, April 2017 - Present Edmonton, Alberta

- Ported existing SaaS website to mobile site using PHP, jQuery, AJAX and Bootstrap
- Built cross platform app (Android, iOS) using React Native and Nodejs that utilizes existing database and syncs with existing live site

Web Developer (Volunteer)

New Tribes Missions (now Éthnos) October 2016 - March 2017 Remote Work

Assisted in building document management system using Aurelia and JavaScript

C# Web Developer (Contractor)

Real Foods Ltd.
December 2013-July 2014
Edinburgh, Scotland

- Developed email content management system using ASP.NET for automated customer service and online orders through the company's e-commerce website
- Developed image optimization task in C# and GraphicsMagick to scale and crop images for company website content to reduce server load
- Developed web scraping scripts in Python with Beautiful Soup to scrape competitors' websites for price and product data
- Developed mobile app in Java using Codename One to scan barcodes for product price comparison
- Advocated adoption of ASP.MVC to facilitate unit testing and proper separation of presentation from business logic

Web Programmer

Dundalk Institute of Technology

May 2012 - August 2012, Dundalk, Ireland

- Designed and developed database backed website for the purpose of recording and reporting on class attendance written in Java using MySql database
- Tested with Junit, automated with Ant

Website and Graphic Designer

Cara Web Design January 2010 – December 2013 Athboy, Ireland

- Developed websites using Drupal, Wordpress and/or HTML/CSS/JavaScript for small businesses and organisations
- Designed graphics for the websites, brochures, business cards and signage

Software Researcher and Designer

Interact Forms Ltd. July 2008 - January 2011 Athboy, Ireland

> Designed software specification and cost benefit analysis for a new business web application with an Enterprise Ireland Innovation Voucher in partnership with Dundalk Institute of Technology

Early Career

Technical Site Supervisor - A-Frame Energy Efficient Homes, Ireland, 2006 - 2007 Company Owner and Builder - Custom Home Builder, Canada, 2002 - 2006 Oil Rig Crew - Precision Drilling, Canada, 1999 - 2001

Education

BSc in Computing (2.1)

Dundalk Institute of Technology September 2009-April 2013 Dundalk, Ireland

Thesis: Benchmarking Servers: Java, Erlang, Tomcat and Yaws

Object Oriented System Analysis and Design Certificate

Southern Alberta Institute of Technology September 1998-April 1999 Calgary, Canada

2D and 3D CAD Certificates

City and Guilds November 2007-June 2008 Dundalk, Ireland

References

Vincent Wansink President, Kwiksol Corporation

Phone: 780 868 5628

Email: vincentwansink@outlook.com

Dr. Christian Horn

Head of Computing Department, Dundalk Institute of Technology, Ireland

Phone: 042 937 0200

Email: christian.horn@dkit.ie

Computer Languages and Skills

Programming Languages: Java, C#, C, C++, Python, Erlang, VBA, PHP

Web Languages: HTML, CSS, XML, JSON, JavaScript, jQuery

Databases: Oracle SQL, MySQL, JDBC, MS SQL

Operating Systems: Windows (10, 7, XP), Linux (Mint, Ubuntu, Scientific), OSX

Artificial Intelligence: Advanced Natural Language Processing, Information Theory, Advanced Vision,

Reinforcement Learning

Development Tools: Eclipse, NetBeans, Visual Studio, Notepad++, Geany (Linux), Sublime, Atom, VS

Code

Design Tools: Photoshop, MS Visio, Balsamiq, Google Drive (Drawing), 3DS Max, GIMP, Blender

Office Tools: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, LaTex, Libre Office, Google Docs

Project Management: Google Drive, Google Calendar, Trello

Systems Design: System Specifications and Design, Distributed Systems, Test Driven Development,

White Box Testing, Black Box Testing

Testing, Automation and Debugging: JUnit, Spring, Ant, Benchmarking

GUI: Java Swing, C++ SDL, Web Interfaces

Servers: Apache HTTP, Apache Tomcat, Yaws, IIS, Nodejs

Version Control: Subversion (SVN), Git

Mobile: Android, Codename One, React Native

Frameworks: Google Web Toolkit, Spring, ASP, .NET, Bootstrap, Angular, React, Beautiful Soup

Etc: Web crawlers, Web scrapers, Load testing

Work Samples

Online Resume: https://agile-crag-54496.herokuapp.com/